#### Contact

info@established1992.com

www.linkedin.com/in/elijah-townsend-55017b50 (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

JavaScript Web Design Web Development

Honors-Awards

2019 Design or Die Challenge Champion

# Elijah Townsend

Senior UI/UX Designer at Envestnet | MoneyGuide

Thomasville, North Carolina, United States

## Summary

Highly motivated technical designer with a coding background. Always seeking to expand my developing knowledge and leadership skills to contribute to the success of the team. With over 9 years of professional experience in interface, experience and interaction design.

## Experience

Envestnet | MoneyGuide Senior UI/UX Designer January 2022 - Present (1 year 2 months)

- Creating and developing user-centred designs based on user group needs in Figma
- Designing and clearly communicating Use Cases, Workflows, Mockups, Wireframes, and Prototypes
- Working with developers throughout the implementation of interactive concepts

Established 1992

Designer, Consultant

January 2012 - Present (11 years 2 months)

- Researched, developed and launched developer resources for Zurb's
   Foundation Framework, identifying changes between version 5 and version 6, foundation.established1992.com
- Creating responsive user interfaces that engage customers across different devices and resolutions
- Establishing user-centered designs by creating user-flows and mockups to present to product owner
- Testing cross browser functionality along with optimizing websites for performance

FindCenter
Senior Experience Designer
June 2021 - January 2022 (8 months)

Page 1 of 4

- Responsible for the experience design of FindCenter.com
- Creating user experiences for web platform that are intuitive, accessible, and highly satisfying.
- Collaborating with product stakeholders by facilitating meetings, clearing confusion behind product requirements, and pushing designs through multidisciplinary reviews.
- Generating simulations and low to high fidelity prototypes for user testing, market research, and business stakeholder reviews with Figma, Zeplin and Adobe Creative Suite.

#### Truist

1 year 7 months

Senior Experience Designer December 2020 - June 2021 (7 months)

- Creating highly usable solutions for web based applications through business requirements, user research, established patterns, design system components and accessibility standards
- Strong work ethic with an inherent sense of ownership and responsibility
- Rapidly produce concepts and prototypes; distinguishing between when to build a prototype or create a hi-fidelity mockup
- Collaborate with designers from different platforms to develop a holistic design for clients

## Senior User Interface Designer

December 2019 - December 2020 (1 year 1 month)

Raleigh-Durham, North Carolina Area

- Building stable and maintainable codebases using Angular
- Performing bug fixes and code review while maintaining an organized workflow using GitLab
- Ensuring proper documentation through all stages of product life cycles
- Implementing company design system into multiple business focus projects
- Creating and pushing reusable components back into design system for entire company to use

#### BB&T

Senior User Interface Designer
June 2018 - December 2019 (1 year 7 months)

Raleigh-Durham, North Carolina Area

• Creating user-centered designs for our enterprise platform, U, with careful consideration for business requirements, user feedback, and usability findings

- Updating U Web with JavaScript, HTML, CSS and Aria attributes to improve accessibility for all users and responsive web design.
- Familiarity of World Wide Web Consortium (W3C) guidelines.
- Significant experience with GIT and SVN versioning management.
- Prototyping in Handlebars to show functionality to team.

Old Dominion Freight Line
UI/UX Designer
April 2013 - June 2018 (5 years 3 months)
Thomasville, NC

- Implemented the UX & UI strategy to transition AS400 applications over to Java applications with a uniform look and feel
- Responsible for designing odfl.com through wireframes, mockups, style guides, and front-end frameworks, with over 30,000 daily users
- Responsible for defining style guide, pattern library and coding standards for internal enterprise applications
- Working in both Agile and Waterfall software development principles
- Meeting with product owners and users to create low/high fidelity mockups and gain usability testing statistics
- Ability to create clickable and functional prototypes through Sketch, Invision or using front-end languages (HTML/CSS/JavaScript)
- Designed a user testing plan utilizing pre-release and post-release user observation tests

#### Civvis

UX Product Design Consultant November 2016 - November 2017 (1 year 1 month) Raleigh-Durham, North Carolina Area

- Conveyed design concepts and deliverables to business partners through in-person and remote presentations as well as through detailed and easily understood documentation.
- Designing, wireframing and prototyping complex, interactive solutions in a very complex solution space
- Work with clients to translate business problems and requirements into compelling UI's that demonstrate the power and value of rich internet experiences.

Market Connection
Web Designer
May 2012 - December 2012 (8 months)
Page 3 of 4

#### Boone, NC

- Ensuring brand guidelines are adhered to each project
- Collaborating with team members to create layouts and engaging designs
- Updating stylesheets and front-end code as needed

## Education

Caldwell Community College and Technical Institute Associates, Web Technologies · (2012 - 2014)